And now we are going to talk about Tool LLM.
이제 Tool LLM에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
In this paper, the main goal is to make a framework
본 논문의 주요 목표는 프레임워크를 만드는 것입니다.
to train LLMs that could use multiple APIs
여러 API를 사용할 수 있는 LLM 교육
to fulfill the textual request from the user.
사용자의 텍스트 요청을 이행합니다.
The solution they provide is called Tool LLM,
그들이 제공하는 솔루션은 Tool LLM이라고 불리며,
which is a general framework.
이는 일반적인 프레임워크입니다.
It has several parts.
여러 부분이 있습니다.
If you want to mention at a very high level
아주 높은 수준에서 언급하고 싶다면
the contributions of this paper.
이 논문의 기여.
First, there is Toolbench, which is a new instruction
먼저 새로운 명령어인 Toolbench가 있습니다.
tuning dataset specifically for tool use.
도구 사용을 위해 특별히 데이터 세트를 조정합니다.
New algorithm called DFS Decision Tree
DFS 결정 트리라는 새로운 알고리즘
that can enhance the reasoning capabilities of LLMs.
LLM의 추론 능력을 향상시킬 수 있습니다.
A new way of evaluating these kind of tools, which
이러한 종류의 도구를 평가하는 새로운 방법은 다음과 같습니다.
is called Tool Eval, and a new fine-tuned LLM based model
Tool Eval이라고 불리는 새로운 미세 조정 LLM 기반 모델
to actually recommend proper sequences of APIs
실제로 적절한 API 시퀀스를 권장합니다.
to fulfill the textual request.
텍스트 요청을 이행합니다.
So the problem with the previous work
그럼 전작의 문제는
and the current status in this area
그리고 이 지역의 현재 상황
is that the best thing we have right now
그게 지금 우리가 가진 것 중 가장 좋은 거야
is chargivity from OpenAI, which is closed source, which
비공개 소스인 OpenAI의 전하성입니다.
is not ideal for all of the users.
모든 사용자에게 이상적인 것은 아닙니다.
And in the open source world, the previous work
그리고 오픈소스 세계에서는 전작이
has several limitations, such as the limited set of APIs
제한된 API 세트와 같은 몇 가지 제한 사항이 있습니다.
or just using fake APIs to train models.
아니면 가짜 API를 사용하여 모델을 훈련할 수도 있습니다.
In some work, the scenarios are very constrained.
일부 작업에서는 시나리오가 매우 제한적입니다.
Either it's only single tool, or they
단일 도구이거나
assume that the user would manually
사용자가 수동으로
specify the ideal set of APIs.
이상적인 API 세트를 지정합니다.
Or in some other works, the planning and reasoning
아니면 다른 작품에서는 기획과 추론이
is very not great.
별로 좋지 않습니다.
So to mitigate all of this issue, the first step
따라서 이 모든 문제를 완화하기 위한 첫 번째 단계는
is making a good dataset.
좋은 데이터 세트를 만들고 있습니다.
They call it Toolbench in this paper.
이 문서에서는 이를 Toolbench라고 부릅니다.
Toolbench is a dataset that has been created using chargivity
Toolbench는 Chargivity를 사용하여 생성된 데이터 세트입니다.
as a teacher model.
선생님 모델로.
And it has been constructed in three general phases.
그리고 그것은 세 가지 일반적인 단계로 구성되었습니다.
First, they collected APIs from Rapid API Hub.
먼저 Rapid API Hub에서 API를 수집했습니다.
In the second phase, they used prompting chargivity
두 번째 단계에서는 전성을 자극하는 방법을 사용했습니다.
to generate instructions for different scenarios.
다양한 시나리오에 대한 지침을 생성합니다.
And in the last step, they annotated the correct path
그리고 마지막 단계에서 올바른 경로에 주석을 달았습니다.
and the correct sequences of APIs that
그리고 올바른 API 시퀀스
would accomplish that task.
그 임무를 완수할 것입니다.
So let's get into the details of this.
그럼 이에 대해 자세히 알아보겠습니다.
So the first step was the API collection.
그래서 첫 번째 단계는 API 수집이었습니다.
In this step, first, they start with more than 53,000 APIs
이 단계에서는 먼저 53,000개 이상의 API로 시작합니다.
from more than 10,000 tools in 49 categories.
49개 카테고리의 10,000개 이상의 도구 중에서 선택하세요.
But many of them are not functional.
그러나 그 중 많은 기능이 작동하지 않습니다.
They are just, if you call it, responses error or something.
당신이 그것을 부르면 그들은 단지 오류라고 응답합니다.
And if you remove all of those things,
그리고 그 것들을 모두 제거하면,
we can end up with more than 16,000 APIs
결국 16,000개가 넘는 API를 갖게 될 수 있습니다.
from more than 3,400 tools.
3,400개 이상의 도구에서.
In the second phase, which is the instruction generation
두 번째 단계에서는 명령어 생성입니다.
phase, the core idea is that we randomly sample
단계에서 핵심 아이디어는 무작위로 샘플링하는 것입니다.
a subset of those APIs that we collected in the previous phase.
이전 단계에서 수집한 API의 하위 집합입니다.
And we feed it to chargivity and ask it
그리고 우리는 그것을 전하에게 먹이고 묻습니다.
to create a sequence of actions for us.
우리를 위한 일련의 작업을 생성합니다.
So the actual prompt for this step
따라서 이 단계에 대한 실제 프롬프트는
contains, at first, the general description
처음에는 일반적인 설명이 포함되어 있습니다.
of this instruction generation task.
이 명령어 생성 작업의
And second, the documentation of those selected APIs.
둘째, 선택한 API에 대한 문서입니다.
And third, there are several seed examples,
셋째, 몇 가지 시드 예시가 있습니다.
specifically three seed examples that
구체적으로 세 가지 시드 예는 다음과 같습니다.
have been written by human experts.
인간 전문가가 작성했습니다.
To make sure that we have diversity in this process,
이 과정에서 다양성을 보장하기 위해,
they generate instructions for three different scenarios.
세 가지 시나리오에 대한 지침을 생성합니다.
First, single tool use scenarios, only one API.
첫째, 단일 도구 사용 시나리오, 단 하나의 API입니다.
One tool would be used.
하나의 도구가 사용됩니다.
The APIs of one tool would be used.
한 도구의 API가 사용됩니다.
And in multi-tool scenario, we have two sub-scenarios,
다중 도구 시나리오에는 두 가지 하위 시나리오가 있습니다.
intra-category and intra-collection.
카테고리 내 및 컬렉션 내.
So in rapid API, half, if you go and see,
따라서 빠른 API에서는 반, 가서 보면
categories are the more coarse-grained kind
카테고리는 좀 더 거친 종류입니다.
of categorization of the APIs.
API 분류.
And collections are more fine-grained.
그리고 컬렉션이 더욱 세분화되었습니다.
So we can have diversity at different levels.
그래서 우리는 다양한 수준에서 다양성을 가질 수 있습니다.
At the category level or at the collection level,
카테고리 수준이나 컬렉션 수준에서
they sample two to three five tools
그들은 2~35개의 도구를 샘플링합니다.
from the same category for collection.
수집을 위해 동일한 카테고리에서.
And for each tool, they sample up to three APIs.
그리고 각 도구에 대해 최대 3개의 API를 샘플링합니다.
And these are going to be collected and set aside.
그리고 이것들은 수집되어 따로 보관될 것입니다.
As you can see in total, there are more than 87,000 single tool
보시다시피 총 87,000개 이상의 단일 도구가 있습니다.
APIs, more than 84,000 multi-tool APIs from the same category
API, 동일한 카테고리의 84,000개 이상의 다중 도구 API
and 24,000 multi-tool APIs from the same collection.
동일한 컬렉션의 24,000개 다중 도구 API.
And in the final phase, we have to annotate the solution panel.
그리고 마지막 단계에서는 솔루션 패널에 주석을 달아야 합니다.
So in this phase, they prompt the attractivity
따라서 이 단계에서는 매력을 자극합니다.
to find the valid action sequence.
유효한 동작 순서를 찾으려면
More specifically, they have strategy
좀 더 구체적으로 말하면 전략이 있습니다.
to tell its top and the API name and the arguments
상단과 API 이름 및 인수를 알려줍니다.
for that API.
해당 API에 대한 것입니다.
To be more specific, they use the function called
좀 더 구체적으로 말하자면, 그들은 다음과 같은 함수를 사용합니다.
feature of the attractivity, and each API
어트랙션의 특징과 각 API
would act as a function, plus two types
함수와 두 가지 유형으로 작동합니다.
of special kinds of APIs as functions.
특별한 종류의 API를 함수로 사용합니다.
One is finished by giving up, and another one
하나는 포기하고 하나는 끝내고
is finished with final insert.
최종 삽입으로 마무리되었습니다.
So if a model reaches finished by giving up function,
그래서 모델이 기능을 포기하고 완성되면,
it means that, OK, this path, this sequence,
즉, 이 경로, 이 순서는
is not going to be valid.
유효하지 않을 것입니다.
And we should abort expanding this sequence.
그리고 우리는 이 시퀀스 확장을 중단해야 합니다.
And this is the place that their new novel idea of reasoning
그리고 이곳은 그들의 새로운 추론 아이디어가 탄생하는 곳이다.
comes into place, which is a DFS-based decision tree.
이는 DFS 기반 의사결정 트리입니다.
To actually find the best sequences
실제로 최고의 시퀀스를 찾으려면
with the highest likelihood of actually reaching a good answer,
실제로 좋은 답변에 도달할 가능성이 가장 높으며,
they use a simple but very effective method.
그들은 간단하지만 매우 효과적인 방법을 사용합니다.
They use DFS to actually expand the nodes,
실제로 노드를 확장하기 위해 DFS를 사용합니다.
and the model says finished by giving up.
모델은 포기하여 끝났다고 말합니다.
They abort the backtrack, and they
그들은 역추적을 중단하고
try to expand another node until they reach the node that
해당 노드에 도달할 때까지 다른 노드를 확장해 보세요.
causes the function to finish with final answer.
함수가 최종 답변으로 끝나도록 합니다.
And that path is going to act as a ground
그리고 그 길은 접지 역할을 할 것입니다
tool in this data set.
이 데이터 세트의 도구입니다.
So data collection aside, we also
따라서 데이터 수집은 제쳐두고 우리는 또한
need to have some way to evaluate tool use LLM.
도구 사용 LLM을 평가할 수 있는 방법이 필요합니다.
And it's pretty obvious that manually annotating
그리고 수동으로 주석을 달면
fixed ground-tools solution is almost impossible.
고정된 지상 공구 솔루션은 거의 불가능합니다.
There are thousands of APIs out there.
세상에는 수천 개의 API가 있습니다.
There are several ways to actually accomplish
실제로 달성하는 방법에는 여러 가지가 있습니다.
one single instruction.
하나의 지시.
So it's pretty obvious that it's invisible.
그래서 눈에 보이지 않는 것이 너무나 당연합니다.
So the basic, most fundamental thing
그래서 가장 기본적이고 가장 근본적인 것은
we could think of is a pass rate.
우리가 생각할 수 있는 것은 합격률입니다.
The sequence of the APIs that have been suggested by LLM
LLM에서 제안한 API의 순서
should be executable within a limited budget.
제한된 예산 내에서 실행 가능해야 합니다.
That's what they call pass rate in their tool
그것이 그들이 도구에서 합격률이라고 부르는 것입니다.
eval, which is an evaluation framework.
평가 프레임워크인 eval.
And they compared it with human evaluation,
그리고 그들은 그것을 인간의 평가와 비교했습니다.
and they found out the agreement rate of 87%.
그리고 87%의 동의율을 알아냈습니다.
The more useful thing is a win rate,
더 유용한 것은 승률입니다.
which gives us a sense of usefulness of that sequence.
이는 우리에게 해당 시퀀스의 유용성을 제공합니다.
The win rate, the idea is that we ask
승률, 아이디어는 우리가 묻는 것입니다
creativity to that which solution path from a pair of solution
한 쌍의 솔루션에서 어떤 솔루션 경로를 선택하는지에 대한 창의성
paths would be preferred, which one is the better one.
경로가 더 선호될 것입니다. 어느 것이 더 나은 경로입니까?
And we do this multiple times, and we take the average,
이 작업을 여러 번 수행하고 평균을 구합니다.
and that would be the winner between these two solution paths.
그리고 그것이 이 두 가지 솔루션 경로 사이에서 승자가 될 것입니다.
So based on this metric, they, again,
따라서 이 측정항목을 기반으로 그들은 다시
did some human evaluation and saw 80% agreement.
사람이 직접 평가한 결과 80%가 일치했습니다.
So another idea of the paper is called API Retriever,
논문의 또 다른 아이디어는 API Retriever입니다.
which is used to find the best set of APIs
최상의 API 세트를 찾는 데 사용됩니다.
that would be relevant to solve a specific request.
이는 특정 요청을 해결하는 데 관련이 있습니다.
And the way that they solve this is pretty simple.
그리고 이 문제를 해결하는 방법은 매우 간단합니다.
We just take the, calculate the embedding similarities
우리는 임베딩 유사성을 취하여 계산합니다.
between the instructions and the documentation of the API.
API의 지침과 문서 사이.
The embeddings have been calculated using dirt.
임베딩은 먼지를 사용하여 계산되었습니다.
But they have done some experiments
하지만 그들은 몇 가지 실험을 해왔습니다.
and showed that this way of finding APIs
API를 찾는 방법을 보여줬습니다.
is way better than the previous ways,
이전 방법보다 훨씬 낫습니다.
namely, BM25 and the Ada model.
즉, BM25와 Ada 모델입니다.
The other idea of the paper, as we discussed,
우리가 논의한 것처럼, 이 논문의 또 다른 아이디어는,
was this DFS-based decision tree.
이것이 바로 DFS 기반 의사결정 트리였습니다.
And they also compared that with the more commonly used method,
그리고 그들은 또한 그것을 더 일반적으로 사용되는 방법과 비교했습니다.
namely React.
즉 리액트.
But to make things fair, because DFS-DT would consume
그러나 일을 공정하게 하기 위해 DFS-DT는
way more API calls, and they run React several end times
훨씬 더 많은 API 호출이 발생하고 React가 여러 번 종료됩니다.
until they reach the same level of API calls.
동일한 수준의 API 호출에 도달할 때까지.
But still, they saw that OK, DFS decision tree
하지만 여전히 그들은 OK, DFS 의사결정 트리를 보았습니다.
outperforms React by a good margin.
React보다 훨씬 뛰어납니다.
And at the core of the paper, we have a fine-tuned
그리고 논문의 핵심에는 미세 조정된
Lama model using all of the data that we discussed.
우리가 논의한 모든 데이터를 사용하는 라마 모델.
And they also increased the input lens from 4,000 to 8,000
그리고 입력 렌즈도 4,000에서 8,000으로 늘렸습니다.
using positional interpolation.
위치 보간을 사용합니다.
They did the evolution at three levels,
그들은 세 가지 수준에서 진화를 했습니다.
of generalizability, let's say, and thumbs-in instruction,
일반화 가능성과 엄지손가락으로 가르칠 수 있는 교육,
thumbs-in tools in the same category,
동일한 카테고리의 엄지 손가락 도구,
thumbs-in tools in different categories.
다양한 카테고리의 엄지 손가락 도구.
And the experiments also have been
그리고 실험은 또한
done in three different scenarios,
세 가지 시나리오에서 수행되었으며
which is corresponding to the data that they collected,
이는 그들이 수집한 데이터에 해당하며,
single-tool, intro category, multi-tool,
단일 도구, 소개 카테고리, 다중 도구,
and intro collection multi-tool.
인트로 컬렉션 멀티툴.
They also used several other baselines, as you can see
또한 보시다시피 몇 가지 다른 기준선도 사용했습니다.
on the slides.
슬라이드에.
And this is the results of the evaluations of the comparison
그리고 이것이 비교평가 결과이다.
between the fine-tuned model, which is called tool Lama,
툴라마(Tool Lama)라고 불리는 미세 조정된 모델 사이,
using different methods of reasoning
다양한 추론 방법을 사용하여
compared with different models.
다른 모델과 비교.
As you can see, other models like Bacuna and Alpaca's
보시다시피 바쿠나나 알파카 같은 다른 모델들도
instruction following abilities are not
지시를 따르는 능력은 그렇지 않습니다.
very useful in this domain, which is tool use.
도구 사용이라는 영역에서 매우 유용합니다.
Also, we see that the DFS decision tree outperforms React
또한 DFS 의사결정 트리가 React보다 성능이 뛰어나다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
in both pass rate and win rate.
합격률과 승률 모두에서요.
And we also see that tool Lama plus DFS decision tree,
또한 Lama 도구와 DFS 의사결정 트리도 볼 수 있습니다.
actually John Street, said very competitive generalization
실제로 John Street는 매우 경쟁적이라고 일반화했습니다.
performance.
성능.
We also see the advantage of the API retriever,
또한 API 검색기의 장점도 확인했습니다.
which in some scenarios, they figure out
어떤 시나리오에서는
it is even better than the ground-throughs in the data set.
이는 데이터 세트의 지상 통과보다 훨씬 좋습니다.
To learn more about the realizationability of tool Lama,
도구 라마의 실현 가능성에 대해 자세히 알아보려면,
they evaluated it out of distribution data set.
그들은 분포 데이터 세트에서 그것을 평가했습니다.
Here, they use API Bench.
여기서는 API Bench를 사용합니다.
They also use both the ground-throughs retriever,
그들은 또한 그라운드 스루 리트리버와
the oracle from that data set, and their own API retriever.
해당 데이터 세트의 Oracle 및 자체 API 검색기.
They also compared the tool Lama with the query log,
그들은 또한 쿼리 로그와 Lama 도구를 비교했으며,
which is the model that have been specifically
이는 특별히 제작된 모델입니다.
trained on this data set.
이 데이터 세트에 대해 교육을 받았습니다.
And as you can see, in both scenarios,
보시다시피 두 시나리오 모두에서
RS here is the retriever over settings.
RS는 설정에 대한 검색기입니다.
It means that retrieved APIs are sent to the model
검색된 API가 모델로 전송된다는 의미입니다.
as part of the prompt.
프롬프트의 일부로.
And ZS is a zero shot.
그리고 ZS는 제로샷입니다.
It means that the APIs are not in the prompt.
이는 API가 프롬프트에 없음을 의미합니다.
So still, we see that the tool Lama can beat a model that
그럼에도 불구하고 우리는 Lama라는 도구가 다음과 같은 모델을 이길 수 있다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
have been trained on this data set.
이 데이터 세트에 대해 교육을 받았습니다.
And in other scenarios, it can actually perform very close
그리고 다른 시나리오에서는 실제로 매우 유사한 성능을 발휘할 수 있습니다.
to a query log.
쿼리 로그에.
OK, now let's talk about tool connectivity, which
자, 이제 도구 연결성에 대해 이야기해 보겠습니다.
takes another approach into learning for LLMs.
LLM 학습에 대한 또 다른 접근 방식을 취합니다.
Well, the fine-tuning LLMs is very
음, 미세 조정 LLM은 매우
expensive in terms of computational costs.
계산 비용 측면에서 비용이 많이 듭니다.
And it's pretty hard to adapt that fine-tune model to new tools.
그리고 미세 조정 모델을 새로운 도구에 적용하는 것은 꽤 어렵습니다.
And also, other techniques, such as in context learning,
또한 상황 학습과 같은 다른 기술도 있습니다.
are pretty limited.
꽤 제한되어 있습니다.
For example, one of the limitations
예를 들어, 제한사항 중 하나는
is that the context list has a limitation for most automotors.
대부분의 자동차 모터에는 컨텍스트 목록이 제한되어 있다는 것입니다.
And for many cases, the future of learning is not effective.
그리고 많은 경우 학습의 미래는 효과적이지 않습니다.
So the key idea in this paper is that we can represent each tool
따라서 이 문서의 핵심 아이디어는 각 도구를 나타낼 수 있다는 것입니다.
as a token.
토큰으로.
And we can augment the vocabulary
그리고 어휘력을 늘릴 수 있어요
at the very beginning of the model.
모델의 맨 처음에.
So during the generation, when the tool can
따라서 생성 중에 도구가
is predicted, the LLM would temporarily
예측되면 LLM은 일시적으로
switch mode to a special tool mode
모드를 특수 도구 모드로 전환
and would reduce proper input arguments
적절한 입력 인수를 줄입니다.
and would call the tool and would inject back
도구를 호출하고 다시 주입합니다.
the result to the output that would generally
일반적으로 출력에 대한 결과
be made in a normal scenario.
정상적인 시나리오에서 수행됩니다.
So you can see in this picture the general architecture
이 그림에서 일반적인 아키텍처를 볼 수 있습니다.
of the tool connectivity.
도구 연결성.
The embeddings are appended to the model head,
임베딩은 모델 헤드에 추가됩니다.
like regular words.
일반적인 단어처럼.
And when a tool can is predicted,
그리고 도구 캔이 예측되면
the LLM switches to the tool mode.
LLM이 도구 모드로 전환됩니다.
And the tool is executed with proper predicted parameters.
그리고 도구는 적절한 예측 매개변수를 사용하여 실행됩니다.
And then the results are going back
그러다가 결과가 돌아오는데
and will be injected in the actual output for the user.
사용자의 실제 출력에 주입됩니다.
So in another way, in terms of mathematics,
그래서 다른 방법으로 수학적인 측면에서
the normal way of predicting the next token
다음 토큰을 예측하는 일반적인 방법
would be just a softmax of the normal words, the vocabulary.
일반적인 단어, 즉 어휘의 소프트맥스일 뿐입니다.
And but right now, we have a softmax over that vocabulary
하지만 지금 당장은 해당 어휘에 대한 소프트맥스가 있습니다.
plus the concatenation of that vocabulary
게다가 해당 어휘의 연결
and the embedding matrix of the tools.
그리고 도구의 임베딩 매트릭스.
So again, to recap, the model by default is in reasoning mode,
다시 요약하자면, 모델은 기본적으로 추론 모드에 있습니다.
tries to generate response normally to the user prompt.
사용자 프롬프트에 정상적으로 응답을 생성하려고 시도합니다.
And then the output is a tool token.
그러면 출력은 도구 토큰입니다.
Instead of a word token, model goes to a tool mode.
단어 토큰 대신 모델이 도구 모드로 전환됩니다.
And in the tool mode, it tries to generate
그리고 도구 모드에서는 생성을 시도합니다.
the proper arguments for the tool.
도구에 대한 적절한 인수.
And in this step, in the tool mode,
그리고 이번 단계에서는 도구 모드에서
we are going to include in the context
우리는 문맥에 포함할 것입니다
the demo for the tool with a special syntax
특수 구문을 사용하는 도구의 데모
and the currently predicted context.
그리고 현재 예측된 상황.
So the training of this model would be something like that.
따라서 이 모델의 훈련은 다음과 같습니다.
So the LLM itself, the weights, could be frozen.
따라서 LLM 자체, 즉 가중치가 동결될 수 있습니다.
And the training data could be a form of the pairs SS
그리고 훈련 데이터는 SS 쌍의 형태일 수 있습니다.
prime. And in the predicted sentence SS
초기. 그리고 예측된 문장 SS에서는
prime, we are going to have a special tokens for tools.
프라임, 우리는 도구에 대한 특별한 토큰을 갖게 될 것입니다.
And for the arguments, we use a special token here in the paper.
그리고 논증을 위해 여기 논문에서는 특별한 토큰을 사용합니다.
They call it NA.
그들은 그것을 NA라고 부릅니다.
That would be ignored in the actual loss function.
이는 실제 손실 함수에서는 무시됩니다.
So if you can see it, if you see the formula,
그래서 만약 여러분이 그것을 볼 수 있다면, 공식을 본다면,
you see that the loss function for those indices would be zero.
해당 인덱스의 손실 함수는 0이 되는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
So we don't care about the argument prediction here.
따라서 우리는 여기서 인수 예측에 관심이 없습니다.
We just want to predict the proper token.
우리는 적절한 토큰을 예측하고 싶을 뿐입니다.
That's how we can train the proper embeddings
이것이 우리가 적절한 임베딩을 훈련할 수 있는 방법입니다.
for the tool tokens.
도구 토큰의 경우.
So there are three experiments in this paper
따라서 이 논문에는 세 가지 실험이 있습니다.
to evaluate this kind of architecture.
이런 종류의 아키텍처를 평가합니다.
First is the arithmetic tools for numerical reasoning.
첫 번째는 수치 추론을 위한 산술 도구입니다.
The second one is the database APIs for knowledge-based
두 번째는 지식기반 데이터베이스 API입니다.
question answering.
질문 답변.
And the third one is robot actions for embodied plan
세 번째는 구체화된 계획을 위한 로봇 액션이다.
generation.
세대.
And we are going to go through them one by one.
그리고 우리는 그것들을 하나씩 살펴볼 것입니다.
So the first one is the numerical reasoning.
첫 번째는 수치적 추론입니다.
The data that they use in this experiment
이번 실험에 사용된 데이터
is actually an enhanced version of the JSON 8K, which
실제로는 JSON 8K의 향상된 버전입니다.
contains some school grade math problems
학교 수준의 수학 문제가 일부 포함되어 있습니다.
with basic arithmetic for operations.
연산을 위한 기본 산술을 사용합니다.
But they added larger numbers to that to make it even harder.
그러나 그들은 그것을 더욱 어렵게 만들기 위해 거기에 더 많은 숫자를 추가했습니다.
And the other data that they use and they actually enhanced
그리고 그들이 사용하고 실제로 향상시킨 다른 데이터
is the font QA, which contains synthetic data
합성 데이터가 포함된 글꼴 QA입니다.
for more complex arithmetic tools like the square power.
제곱제곱과 같은 더 복잡한 산술 도구의 경우.
So this data set is going to be a little bit
따라서 이 데이터 세트는 약간
like very smaller than the first one.
첫 번째 것보다 아주 작은 것 같아요.
It only contains 68 one hop and 60 multi hop questions.
여기에는 68개의 단일 홉 질문과 60개의 다중 홉 질문만 포함되어 있습니다.
Other than the data that they use in several models
여러 모델에서 사용하는 데이터 외에
to compare with zero shot creativity,
제로샷 창의성과 비교하자면,
chain of thoughts, LAMA-based LLN,
생각의 사슬, LAMA 기반 LLN,
they use 33 billion parameters LAMA.
그들은 330억 개의 매개변수 LAMA를 사용합니다.
Also, they use their React reasoning method.
또한 그들은 React 추론 방법을 사용합니다.
So it's important to note that tool embeddings
따라서 도구 임베딩이
are only trained on the one hop synthetic data.
단일 홉 합성 데이터에 대해서만 훈련됩니다.
But still, as you can see on the results table,
하지만 여전히 결과표에서 볼 수 있듯이
they manage to perform pretty good in the multi hop problems.
그들은 다중 홉 문제에서 꽤 좋은 성능을 발휘했습니다.
So they could be incorporated in something
그래서 그들은 무언가에 통합될 수 있었습니다
like a chain of thought prompting.
생각의 연쇄처럼.
The second experiment is knowledge-based question
두 번째 실험은 지식 기반 질문입니다.
answering.
응답.
The data set they use is Camel, which
그들이 사용하는 데이터 세트는 Camel입니다.
contains a lot of relational knowledge from Wikipedia.
Wikipedia의 많은 관계형 지식이 포함되어 있습니다.
There are 243 relations and there are subsets
243개의 관계가 있고 하위 집합이 있습니다.
of size 500 with different numbers of tools in this data set.
이 데이터 세트에는 다양한 수의 도구가 포함된 크기 500입니다.
So for comparison sake, the models
그래서 비교를 위해 모델들은
that they developed like fine-tuned for this experiment,
이 실험을 위해 미세 조정된 것처럼 개발된 것입니다.
the variations of toolkit and GBT are two variations.
툴킷과 GBT의 변형은 두 가지 변형입니다.
One is the supervised learning variation
하나는 지도 학습 변형입니다.
using 200 examples per tool from the data set
데이터 세트의 도구당 200개 예시 사용
that I mentioned above.
위에서 언급한 것.
And another variation is synthetic tool
또 다른 변형은 합성 도구입니다.
can GBT, which is trained on 4D synthesized data
4D 합성 데이터로 훈련된 GBT 가능
using prompting chat GBT.
프롬프트 채팅 GBT를 사용합니다.
The prompting is just putting the question
프롬프트는 질문을 넣는 것뿐입니다.
and saying that the answer is and getting
대답은 다음과 같다고 말하고
that answer from chat GBT.
채팅 GBT의 답변입니다.
So as a baseline, they used in-context learning
그래서 그들은 기준으로 상황 내 학습을 사용했습니다.
in two variations.
두 가지 변형으로.
One is the view shot, in which they put the description
하나는 설명을 넣은 뷰 샷입니다.
of the tools and the demo of those tools in the prompt.
도구에 대한 설명과 해당 도구의 데모가 프롬프트에 표시됩니다.
But in a zero-shot setting, in-context learning,
하지만 제로샷 환경에서 상황에 맞는 학습은
they put the description of the tools,
도구에 대한 설명을 적어 놓았고,
but they put eight demo of unavailable tools
하지만 사용할 수 없는 도구에 대한 8가지 데모를 게시했습니다.
just to teach a model how it could generate
모델이 어떻게 생성될 수 있는지 가르치기 위해
the proper calling format of the functions.
함수의 적절한 호출 형식.
The base model they use for comparison for the baselines
기준선 비교를 위해 사용하는 기본 모델
are Lama 13 billion parameters.
라마의 매개변수는 130억 개입니다.
As we can see in the results chart,
결과 차트에서 볼 수 있듯이,
here the LLMs still struggle to store accurate facts
여기서 LLM은 여전히 ​​정확한 사실을 저장하는 데 어려움을 겪고 있습니다.
in the parameter, so we have to have some kind of supervised
매개변수에서 일종의 감독을 받아야 합니다.
learning to actually augment them with the knowledge
실제로 지식을 강화하는 방법을 학습
that they need.
그들이 필요로하는 것.
And as you can see, to look at this idea,
보시다시피 이 아이디어를 살펴보면
the core idea of the paper is pretty effective method
논문의 핵심 아이디어는 꽤 효과적인 방법입니다
on understanding and using a massive amount of in-domain data.
방대한 양의 도메인 내 데이터를 이해하고 활용하는 방법에 대해 알아봅니다.
And another point to mention here is that the context length
여기서 언급할 또 다른 점은 컨텍스트 길이입니다.
limits actually makes a huge impact on the performance
한도는 실제로 성능에 큰 영향을 미칩니다.
of the models when we increase the number of relations
관계 수를 늘릴 때 모델의
of tools in the test sets.
테스트 세트의 도구.
So in the third experiment, which they call
그래서 그들이 부르는 세 번째 실험에서는
embodied plan generation, they use the activity programs
구체화된 계획 생성, 활동 프로그램 사용
knowledge-based, which is on top of the virtual home platform.
가상 홈 플랫폼 위에 있는 지식 기반.
This knowledge-based is comprised
지식기반으로 구성되어 있습니다.
of typical household activities.
전형적인 집안 활동.
So one task would look like something like, OK,
따라서 하나의 작업은 다음과 같습니다.
there's a goal, for example, a reading book or a book.
예를 들어 독서 책이나 책과 같은 목표가 있습니다.
And a detailed instruction, for example,
예를 들어 자세한 지침은 다음과 같습니다.
I would go lie down in my bed and open the book
나는 침대에 누워서 책을 펴곤 했어
and start reading.
그리고 읽기 시작하세요.
And also the description of the environment.
그리고 환경에 대한 설명도 있습니다.
One part of that description is the initial state of the agent.
해당 설명의 한 부분은 에이전트의 초기 상태입니다.
And another part is the object list in the environment.
그리고 또 다른 부분은 환경의 개체 목록입니다.
For example, they say, I am in office home,
예를 들어, 그들은 내가 사무실 집에 있다고 말합니다.
and the objects I can manipulate are mail, freezer,
그리고 제가 조작할 수 있는 물건은 우편물, 냉동고,
television, and stuff.
텔레비전, 그리고 물건.
And the model is expected to output an executable plan,
그리고 모델은 실행 가능한 계획을 출력할 것으로 예상됩니다.
which is basically an ordered list of verb object instructions.
이는 기본적으로 동사 목적어 명령의 순서가 지정된 목록입니다.
For example, find novel.
예를 들어 소설을 찾으세요.
OK, for comparison, they used three different baselines.
좋습니다. 비교를 위해 세 가지 다른 기준을 사용했습니다.
First, they only used a basic LLN, which
첫째, 그들은 기본적인 LLN만을 사용했습니다.
is a LLN model, 13 billion parameters.
LLN 모델이며 130억 개의 매개변수가 있습니다.
And simply they use in-context learning.
그리고 그들은 단순히 상황 내 학습을 사용합니다.
They put the action list, three demo plans,
그들은 행동 목록, 세 가지 데모 계획,
a new task with the goal, detailed description,
목표가 있는 새로운 작업, 자세한 설명,
and the environment description.
그리고 환경 설명입니다.
In the third, sorry, in the second variation,
세 번째에서는 죄송합니다. 두 번째 변형에서는
they used translation on top of that.
게다가 번역도 사용했어요.
This idea is that, OK, in some scenarios,
이 아이디어는 일부 시나리오에서는
the model would probably generate some tools
모델은 아마도 몇 가지 도구를 생성할 것입니다.
that are objects that are not actually
그것은 실제로 존재하지 않는 객체입니다.
grounded in the environment.
환경에 기반을 두고 있습니다.
Now we can use a translation model
이제 번역 모델을 사용할 수 있습니다
to translate the outputs from the LLN
LLN의 출력을 번역하기 위해
to the actual grounded facts, the objects in the environment.
실제 근거가 있는 사실, 환경 속의 사물에 대한 것입니다.
They use sentence for virtual large to do this.
그들은 이것을 하기 위해 가상의 큰 문장을 사용합니다.
And in the third step, on top of those previous steps,
세 번째 단계에서는 이전 단계에 더해
they used grounded decoding, which actually
그들은 실제로 접지된 디코딩을 사용했습니다.
incorporates the grounding at the decoding level.
디코딩 레벨에서 접지를 통합합니다.
So we can see that translation actually
그래서 우리는 실제로 그 번역을 볼 수 있습니다
helps solving some shallow grounding problems,
얕은 접지 문제를 해결하는 데 도움이 됩니다.
but grounded decoding further improves that.
그러나 접지 디코딩은 이를 더욱 향상시킵니다.
As you can see, Toolken GPT approach
보시다시피 Toolken GPT 접근 방식
significantly improves the LLN's performance.
LLN의 성능을 크게 향상시킵니다.
Here in this table, the grounding column
여기 이 표에서 접지 컬럼은
shows a proportion of the outputs that are actually
실제로 출력되는 비율을 보여줍니다.
valid and grounded to the environment.
유효하고 환경에 접지되어 있습니다.
Executables are the actual actions
실행 파일은 실제 작업입니다.
that are valid and could be executed.
유효하고 실행될 수 있습니다.
Success are the outputs that actually end
성공은 실제로 끝나는 출력입니다.
with the correct and successful state.
정확하고 성공적인 상태입니다.
And success R is the relaxed version of success
그리고 성공 R은 성공의 편안한 버전입니다.
that it doesn't necessarily finish or end with the proper
반드시 적절한 것으로 끝나거나 끝나는 것은 아닙니다.
state, but at some point in the past,
상태이지만 과거 어느 시점에는
it actually saw the output at the successful state.
실제로 성공적인 상태에서 출력을 보았습니다.
So in terms of computational cost,
따라서 계산 비용 측면에서
we can see that fine tuning with Laura
Laura의 미세 조정을 볼 수 있습니다.
is way more costly, but the actual performance
비용이 훨씬 더 많이 들지만 실제 성능은
is a little bit better.
조금 더 좋습니다.
And to do this competition cost comparison,
그리고 이러한 경쟁 비용 비교를 수행하려면
they used the LAMA 7 billion parameters.
그들은 LAMA 70억 개의 매개변수를 사용했습니다.
In another evaluation study, they
또 다른 평가 연구에서는
showed that they compared the pure react method with a,
그들은 순수한 반응 방법을 a와 비교했음을 보여주었습니다.
and they also added the tool mode, and they compared that,
그리고 도구 모드도 추가해서 비교했습니다.
and they saw that just adding this tool mode actually
그들은 실제로 이 도구 모드를 추가하는 것만으로도
improves the performance of vanilla react
바닐라 반응의 성능을 향상시킵니다.
pretty significantly.
꽤 크게.
So the final thing about this paper
그럼 이 논문의 마지막 내용은
is that there are several decisions in terms of training
훈련과 관련해 여러 가지 결정이 내려진다는 것입니다.
data.
데이터.
They wanted to see what is the effect of synthetic data
그들은 합성 데이터의 효과가 무엇인지 알고 싶었습니다.
supervised data, and they chose different portions
데이터를 감독하고 서로 다른 부분을 선택했습니다.
of training examples from Camel, and they saw that using
Camel의 훈련 예시를 보고 그들은 다음을 사용하여
supervised data actually outperforms
지도 데이터는 실제로 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
the synthetic data with a very high margin.
마진이 매우 높은 합성 데이터.
OK, now we are going to talk about the COG agent paper.
자, 이제 COG 에이전트 문서에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
The core contribution of this paper
이 논문의 핵심 기여
is a BLM that is specializing in agree understanding and planning,
공감 이해와 기획을 전문으로 하는 BLM 입니다.
and also have the general cross modality abilities.
또한 일반적인 교차 양식 능력도 가지고 있습니다.
There are other contributions for this paper as well,
이 논문에는 다른 기여도 있습니다.
like a larger scale, they released a larger scale
더 큰 규모처럼 더 큰 규모를 출시했습니다.
annotated data set about graph theory interfaces and OCR,
그래프 이론 인터페이스 및 OCR에 대한 주석이 달린 데이터 세트,
and they also made a new separate model
그리고 그들은 또한 새로운 별도의 모델을 만들었습니다
to extract features from a high-res UI interface.
고해상도 UI 인터페이스에서 기능을 추출합니다.
The architecture of COG agent is as follows.
COG 에이전트의 아키텍처는 다음과 같습니다.
The core we have COG BLM from previous papers,
우리가 이전 논문에서 COG BLM을 가지고 있는 핵심은,
which has 17 billion parameters.
170억 개의 매개변수가 있습니다.
It also comes with a low-res image encoder
저해상도 이미지 인코더도 함께 제공됩니다.
that can encode very coarse-grained pixels,
매우 거친 픽셀을 인코딩할 수 있는
and on top of this is a multi-layer adapter
그리고 그 위에는 다층 어댑터가 있습니다
that can transform the output of the low-res encoder
저해상도 인코더의 출력을 변환할 수 있는
to the feature space of the BLM.
BLM의 기능 공간에.
And one of the main contributions of this paper
그리고 이 논문의 주요 공헌 중 하나는
is a high-res image encoder that you can see is injected
볼 수 있는 고해상도 이미지 인코더가 삽입되어 있습니다.
using the cross-attention mechanism at each layer
각 레이어에서 Cross-Attention 메커니즘을 사용
to the BLM decoder.
BLM 디코더에.
So for pre-training this model, they
따라서 이 모델을 사전 훈련하기 위해 그들은
focus on three different aspects.
세 가지 다른 측면에 중점을 둡니다.
First is the capability to recognize text of various sizes
첫째, 다양한 크기의 텍스트를 인식하는 능력이다.
or indications on fonts in high-res images.
또는 고해상도 이미지의 글꼴 표시.
Second one is the grounding ability of text
두 번째는 텍스트의 접지 능력이다.
on objects in the image.
이미지 속 개체에 대해
And the third one is the special understanding capability
그리고 세 번째는 특별한 이해능력이다.
for GUI mysteries such as webpages.
웹페이지와 같은 GUI 미스터리의 경우.
And we're going to go through them one by one.
그리고 우리는 그것들을 하나씩 살펴볼 것입니다.
The first one is the texture organization,
첫 번째는 텍스처 구성이고,
and the data that they use is synthetic renderings
그들이 사용하는 데이터는 합성 렌더링입니다.
of text from language pre-training data set.
언어 사전 훈련 데이터 세트의 텍스트입니다.
They basically sample text from the Layon2B data set
기본적으로 Layon2B 데이터 세트의 텍스트를 샘플링합니다.
and used various font sizes and color
다양한 글꼴 크기와 색상을 사용했습니다.
door intentions, different backgrounds
문 의도, 다른 배경
to render different types of text-rich images.
다양한 유형의 텍스트가 풍부한 이미지를 렌더링합니다.
And the second data that they use
그리고 그들이 사용하는 두 번째 데이터는
is an OCR optical character recognition
OCR 광학 문자 인식입니다.
of natural images.
자연스러운 이미지의
They extracted these images from Kaio and Layon2B
Kaio와 Layon2B에서 이미지를 추출했습니다.
with the extracted text with the course
코스와 함께 추출된 텍스트로
of the bounding boxes around.
주변의 경계 상자 중
And the third one is the academy documents
그리고 세번째는 학원서류에요
from archive, which is basically a data set of image text pairs.
기본적으로 이미지 텍스트 쌍의 데이터 세트인 아카이브에서.
The second category of the data or the focus
데이터 또는 초점의 두 번째 범주
of the pre-training is a visual grounding,
사전 훈련의 시각적 접지는
and they used image caption pairs from the Layon115 million
그들은 Layon115million의 이미지 캡션 쌍을 사용했습니다.
data set, which actually has the bounding boxes
실제로 경계 상자가 있는 데이터 세트
of the entities in the caption.
캡션에 있는 항목 중
So the last one is the GUI imagery category
마지막은 GUI 이미지 카테고리입니다.
category for pre-training.
사전 훈련 카테고리입니다.
Again, here we have two different subsets of data.
다시 말하지만, 여기에는 두 가지 서로 다른 데이터 하위 집합이 있습니다.
One is the GUI-referring expression generation,
하나는 GUI 참조 표현식 생성이고,
and the second one is the GUI-referring expression
두 번째는 GUI 참조 표현식입니다.
comprehension.
이해력.
On the generation, the model is basically
해당 세대 모델은 기본적으로
tasked with generating HTML code for DOM elements
DOM 요소에 대한 HTML 코드 생성을 담당합니다.
based in the one specific area of the screenshot.
스크린샷의 특정 영역을 기반으로 합니다.
And on the comprehension task, the data task model
그리고 이해 과제에서는 데이터 과제 모델이
to create the bounding box given a DOM element.
DOM 요소가 주어진 경계 상자를 생성합니다.
They actually created a data set of 400,000 web pages
그들은 실제로 400,000개의 웹페이지로 구성된 데이터 세트를 만들었습니다.
using this structure.
이 구조를 사용합니다.
And they pre-trained CogAgent for 60,000 iterations.
그리고 그들은 60,000번의 반복을 위해 CogAgent를 사전 훈련했습니다.
And on top of that, they further fine-tuned it
게다가, 그들은 그것을 더욱 세밀하게 조정했습니다.
on several different diverse tasks.
여러 가지 다양한 작업에 대해.
The first one is that they collected a lot of screenshots
첫 번째는 스크린샷을 많이 수집했다는 점입니다.
of phones and computer with annotated screen elements
주석이 달린 화면 요소가 있는 휴대폰 및 컴퓨터
and potential tasks and methods of operation.
잠재적인 업무와 운영 방법.
And they also used two famous data sets, Mind2Web
그리고 그들은 또한 두 개의 유명한 데이터 세트인 Mind2Web을 사용했습니다.
and Android in the world, which is more focused on the web
그리고 세계 속의 안드로이드는 웹에 더 집중하고 있습니다
and Android, respectively.
그리고 각각 안드로이드.
And they also used some other miscellaneous VQA data sets
그리고 그들은 또한 기타 기타 VQA 데이터 세트도 사용했습니다.
to find in their model.
그들의 모델에서 찾아보세요.
So on the experiments, we have three categories
실험에는 세 가지 범주가 있습니다.
of experiments.
실험의.
The first experiment is on the foundational visual
첫 번째 실험은 기본 시각적 요소에 관한 것입니다.
understanding.
이해.
They just wanted to make sure that the CogAgent is
그들은 CogAgent가 올바른지 확인하고 싶었습니다.
capable of basic understanding or general understanding,
기본적인 이해나 전반적인 이해가 가능하며,
visual understanding in the domain of VQA.
VQA 영역의 시각적 이해.
They used some general VQA data sets,
그들은 몇 가지 일반적인 VQA 데이터 세트를 사용했습니다.
such as VQAV2 and OKVQA.
VQAV2 및 OKVQA와 같은.
And also, they used a bunch of text rich VQA data sets
또한 그들은 텍스트가 풍부한 VQA 데이터 세트를 많이 사용했습니다.
to fine-tune and also test their model.
모델을 미세 조정하고 테스트하기도 합니다.
And as you can see, CogAgent reaches a state of the art
보시다시피 CogAgent는 최첨단 기술에 도달했습니다.
or very near to the state of the art in almost all of them.
또는 거의 모든 분야에서 최첨단 기술에 매우 가깝습니다.
They also conducted a zero shot test of their model
그들은 또한 자사 모델의 제로샷 테스트를 실시했습니다.
on two challenging out-of-distribution data
두 가지 도전적인 분포를 벗어난 데이터에 대해
sets, so they didn't train or fine-tune their model
그래서 그들은 모델을 훈련하거나 미세 조정하지 않았습니다.
on this data data set.
이 데이터 데이터 세트에 대해.
And still, they saw that the generalizability
그럼에도 불구하고 그들은 일반화가 가능하다는 것을 알았습니다.
of the CogAgent is remarkable.
CogAgent의 기능은 놀랍습니다.
So on the second experiment, we have a GUI agent
두 번째 실험에서는 GUI 에이전트가 있습니다.
on the computer interfaces or actually web interfaces.
컴퓨터 인터페이스 또는 실제로 웹 인터페이스에서.
The data set they used here mainly is a mine-to-web data
여기서 주로 사용한 데이터 세트는 Mine-to-Web 데이터입니다.
set, which is the data set that has more than 2,000
세트는 2,000개가 넘는 데이터 세트입니다.
tasks from 137 websites across 31 different domains.
31개 도메인에 걸쳐 137개 웹사이트의 작업.
And each entry in the data set is comprised
그리고 데이터 세트의 각 항목은 다음과 같이 구성됩니다.
of a high-level task description, a sequence of actions,
높은 수준의 작업 설명, 일련의 작업,
and a web page snapshot in a veritable format.
그리고 실제 형식의 웹페이지 스냅샷입니다.
And given these things, the model should
그리고 이러한 사항을 고려할 때 모델은
predict subsequent or the next action.
후속 또는 다음 행동을 예측합니다.
And they are fine-tuned their model on the mining set
그리고 그들은 마이닝 세트에서 모델을 미세 조정했습니다.
and evaluated on the three different out-of-domain subsets,
세 가지 서로 다른 도메인 외부 하위 집합에 대해 평가되었습니다.
the cross-website, cross-domain, and cross-task.
웹사이트 간, 도메인 간, 작업 간.
As you can see, again, the CogAgent
보시다시피 CogAgent는
can beat a simple famous model.
단순한 유명 모델을 이길 수 있습니다.
So there's LOMA2 or GBT4 in these scenarios.
따라서 이러한 시나리오에는 LOMA2 또는 GBT4가 있습니다.
The last experiment is on smart-mine interfaces,
마지막 실험은 스마트 광산 인터페이스에 관한 것입니다.
and they use Android in the wild.
그들은 실제로 Android를 사용합니다.
As their data set, Android in the wild
데이터 세트로서 Android는 야생에 있습니다.
has more than 700,000 operation episodes,
700,000개 이상의 작업 에피소드를 보유하고 있으며,
covering more than 3,000 task instructions
3,000개 이상의 작업 지침을 다룹니다.
for four different Android versions and 8 device styles,
4가지 Android 버전과 8가지 기기 스타일에 대해
which they have different sizes.
크기가 다릅니다.
So again, similar to the previous one,
그럼 다시 이전과 비슷하게,
each episode in this data set consists
이 데이터 세트의 각 에피소드는 다음과 같이 구성됩니다.
of a goal description in natural language,
자연어로 된 목표 설명,
followed by a sequence of actions
일련의 작업이 뒤따릅니다.
and corresponding screenshots.
그리고 해당 스크린샷.
And the task is to predict the next action based
그리고 임무는 다음 행동을 예측하는 것입니다.
on the given data, mainly based on the given goal.
주로 주어진 목표를 기반으로 주어진 데이터에 대해.
So again, we see that CogAgent can reach a set of the art
다시 한번 우리는 CogAgent가 예술적인 수준에 도달할 수 있다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
and beat the set of the order in most of the sections
대부분의 섹션에서 세트 순서를 이겼습니다.
of this data set.
이 데이터 세트의.
They've done a bunch of ablation studies.
그들은 많은 절제 연구를 수행했습니다.
So the first one is on the they wanted
그래서 첫 번째는 그들이 원했던 것입니다
to actually empirically verify the performance
실제로 성능을 경험적으로 검증하기 위해
gain of the cross-attention mechanism
교차주의 메커니즘의 이득
for encoding high-res images.
고해상도 이미지를 인코딩하기 위한 것입니다.
And we see that computationally speaking,
그리고 우리는 계산적으로 말하자면,
when if you just feed the original model
원래 모델을 공급하면
without that cross-attention with a very high-res image,
매우 높은 해상도의 이미지로 교차주의 없이
the cost is going to go very, very higher.
비용은 매우, 매우 높아질 것입니다.
They also did compare with the different kinds of settings
그들은 또한 다양한 종류의 설정과 비교했습니다.
of using the high-res module and not using the high-res module
고해상도 모듈을 사용하는 것과 고해상도 모듈을 사용하지 않는 것
and with different input sizes.
입력 크기가 다릅니다.
And as you can see, the cross-module idea actually
보시다시피, 크로스 모듈 아이디어는 실제로
enables us to perform way better with way lower cost.
훨씬 더 낮은 비용으로 훨씬 더 나은 성과를 낼 수 있습니다.
And in another ablation study, they
그리고 또 다른 절제 연구에서는
wanted to check the effect of the pre-trained data.
사전 훈련된 데이터의 효과를 확인하고 싶었습니다.
They, in a sequence, first used the image caption data,
그들은 순차적으로 먼저 이미지 캡션 데이터를 사용했고,
then they added the OCR data, and then added the GUI
그런 다음 OCR 데이터를 추가하고 GUI를 추가했습니다.
grounding data.
접지 데이터.
And as we can see, specifically on the mind-to-wet column,
그리고 우리가 볼 수 있듯이, 특히 정신-습식 열에서,
the beveling grounding data have a significant impact
베벨 접지 데이터는 상당한 영향을 미칩니다
on this data set.
이 데이터 세트에 대해.
So it shows the importance of constructing domain-specific
따라서 도메인별 구성의 중요성을 보여줍니다.
pre-trained data.
사전 훈련된 데이터.
Then we want to train GUI agents.
그런 다음 GUI 에이전트를 교육하고 싶습니다.
So in summary, you have seen a tool
요약하자면, 당신은 도구를 보았습니다.
former, which is a general idea of finding LLMs with tool use.
전자는 도구를 사용하여 LLM을 찾는 일반적인 아이디어입니다.
ART, which is a framework for problem decomposition.
ART는 문제 분해를 위한 프레임워크입니다.
AgentBench, which is LLM as agent benchmark.
AgentBench는 에이전트 벤치마크로서의 LLM입니다.
We saw the tool LLM paper, which gave us the idea of how
우리는 LLM 도구 도구를 보고 방법에 대한 아이디어를 얻었습니다.
we can modify LLMs to use multiple APIs with enhanced
향상된 기능을 갖춘 여러 API를 사용하도록 LLM을 수정할 수 있습니다.
reasoning.
추리.
Obviously, the tool can GPT paper that
분명히 이 도구는 GPT 문서를 작성할 수 있습니다.
gave us the idea how to augment LLMs with a massive number
LLM을 엄청나게 늘리는 방법에 대한 아이디어를 제공했습니다.
of tools.
도구의.
And lastly, we saw a cog agent that gave us the idea
그리고 마지막으로 우리는 우리에게 아이디어를 준 톱니바퀴 에이전트를 보았습니다.
how we can create a LLM that can understand higher GUI
더 높은 GUI를 이해할 수 있는 LLM을 만드는 방법
interfaces and the reason about them and plan.
인터페이스와 그에 대한 이유와 계획.